dhyanapeetam.org 2011-04-11

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

dhyanapeetam.org

Effective June 15, 2006

Dhyanapeetam is committed to safeguarding the privacy of its on-line users' Personal information. Please read the following policy to understand the rules and procedures followed by Dhyanapeetam in handling Personal information provided to us over the internet. 

**What information does Dhyanapeetam collect?**

Dhyanapeetam collects the Personal information only from persons who contact us and voluntarily provide the information to us or that is given to us by various affiliated organizations (satsangs and centers) that have your permission to share your Personal information. *Personal information* means your name, shipping/mailing address, telephone number, fax number, and email address and may include your program registration and donation preferences. We do not collect credit or debit card account numbers through our website. All financial transactions such as payment for our programs and donations done through our website are processed by Paypal, an independent third party online payment processing company. Users may review the terms of use and privacy policy for Paypal at [www.paypal.com](http://www.paypal.com/). 

**How Dhyanapeetam uses the Personal Information**

  1. We use your personal information to respond to and fulfill requests for products and services including: Sending information about the activities of Dhyanapeetam, and our affiliates.
  2. Sending you our e-newsletters
  3. Contacting you about the status of your orders, and program registrations
  4. Completing your program registrations

**When we disclose personal information to others**

  1. Dhyanapeetam does exchange Personal information with various affiliated organizations (satsangs and centers) in India. and abroad so that they can contact people on the mailing list about Dhyanapeetam's programs and events.
  2. Dhyanapeetam's mailing list, including the Personal information we receive through the internet, is never shared with any commercial organizations and is never sold, rented or given to unrelated third parties.
  3. Dhyanapeetam will disclose Personal information to third parties if we believe in good faith that the law requires us to do so.

**Right to control and procedures to protect personal information**

  1. Individuals who wish to register online for our programs and events are allowed to register online using the Register button on our website by providing their name, address, email id, and telephone number.
  2. Dhyanapeetam provides links to affiliated entities. These sites operate independently of Dhyanapeetam. Dhyanapeetam is not responsible for the privacy, terms of use or other policies of any other web site. 

**How we use Cookies**

Dhyanapeetam does not use cookies to store information. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored in your computer's hard drive.

**Amendment of Policy**

Dhyanapeetam reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy any time. No individual notice of such changes will be provided but they will appear on the website in the form of a revised and newly dated Privacy Policy. Our current policy was amended June 15, 2006.
